Whoa! This is practically a festival!
I never knew the Mototokage race
was this popular!
Yeah! And today’s the final day,
so everyone’s especially excited!
Whoa! The real thing!
Mototokage. Ride Pokémon.
Dragon/Normal type.
Apparently, it’s been letting people
ride on its back since ancient times.
Depictions of this have been found
in murals from ten thousand years ago.
They’re that old?!
Huh? W-Wait!
Geez, always the same story
with little kids...
Hey!
They’re selling ice cream here!
What?!
I’m coming! I’m coming!
Me too!
Good idea!
Hrrm...
What do I pick...?
Ice cream’s nice,
but so are sandwiches...
Masquernya,
they’ve got matcha ice cream!
Ooh, it’s you lot.
What a coincidence!
Ms. Raifort!
Are you here to
watch the race too, miss?
Well, that too, but actually...
There’s a flea market open throughout the race days,
so I’m on the prowl for old documents.
And I’m in a good mood
thanks to a lucky haul!
So let me treat you
to anything you’d like.
All right!
Huh?
Colza-san?
Back in a minute.
‘Kay!
Hey! That’s my—
Wah!
Ahh, sorry!
Ult, you’ve got to be careful.
You all right?
I’ll just go... wash this off.
Yeah, we’ll wait for ya!
Huh? I thought he went this way...
Ready, set, and... GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Put our palms together, raise them high, and let our lights unite
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
In rain, gales, or even blizzards
We can laugh together as friends
All of the gaps in the Index
let’s fill them in bit by bit
If you’re trying to be someone else
Don’t think like that
You’re fine just as you are
Don’t lose yourself
Recollect on what’s in your pocket
This is what makes us strong
A heartfelt bond that will never fade
Ready, set, and...
GO! READY! GO!
We’re in top-notch mode
You’re not alone, you know?
Let’s fly, higher and higher!
It’s fine to make mistakes
just rest your wings
When you’ve caught your breath
you can fly off once more!
Come along with us, oh-oh
Voltteccers
Pass the endlessly turning seasons,
and venture into brand-new skies
Koraidon & Miraidon! The Great Paldea Race!!
It’s pretty large...
Is this a Mototokage, too?
You okay?!
Maybe you’re not feeling well...?
Huh? Huh?!
Could that mean...?
Are you hungry?
Well? Wanna try some? It’s tasty.
Maybe it’s feeling weak...
Hey, it’s okay now.
Come here.
I know!
Are you hungry?
Mmhm!
Here, it’s tasty!
Thank goodness! Have some more.
They’re taking a long time...
Neither of them is picking up...
The race is about to begin, too...
Ah well, we’ll just have to
leave without them.
Mototokage, the Pokémon that has lived alongside
Paldea’s humans since old times!
It enjoys giving rides to humans, and it is that very habit
which led to the birth of our Mototokage Race.
And this race, the 103rd,
has reached its final day!
For commentary, we have Hassaku-san
of the Paldea League Elite Four in attendance.
Huh?! For real?!
Who better to call upon for Dragon types?
I shall provide impeccable commentary!
The course for the finals
starts right here in Bowl Town,
and heads through the South Area’s
mountains and valleys to Cercle Town.
From there, they’ll head east,
setting their sights on the goal of Table City.
You’re taking part in the race, right?
Where’s your trainer?
Let’s go to the starting line together!
Currently in first place,
defending their four-win streak,
is Mover Foods, led by the champion,
Competitor Tobashitenno!
With the great man of the mountain stages,
Competitor Noborio,
and the stormy sprinter Competitor Tyler,
we can look forward to some finely coordinated racing!
On their tail are last year’s
second place team, Paldea Postal.
Followed by the first-time entrants
from the Johto Region, the Dragon Biker Gang!
Huh? The Dragon Biker Gang?
Huh?
Ride on!
What?!
And the Scovillain is out!
The starting gun for the final stretch
is finally about to fire!
Wha—?!
Hey, hold on!
What?!
What’s gotten into you?
South Area 5 is a mountainous stage
with large ups and downs!
I’ll break ahead!
Mototokage! Gear Change!
Paldea Postal’s mountain pro,
Competitor Vincent, pulls ahead!
What’s this?
It seems someone else
is joining the group!
Could those be
spectators’ Mototokage?
Liko?! Roy?!
Hmm...?
Could those Pokémon be...?
After them!
Huh? What’s the rush...?
Beats me,
but it sounds innerestin’!
Wait!
Liko?! What’re you doing?
Roy!
I was just trying to bring this lost Mototokage
back to the race, and it suddenly took off running...
Same here.
But it won’t listen to a thing I say...
Hassaku-san, your thoughts?
With surprise entrants in this leg,
just what can we expect?
Compared to the mostly level grounds we saw yesterday,
this course may be tough for the average Mototokage to run.
However! I do get the feeling
we may witness something unexpected here!
Come on!
Settle down!
Huh?!
Waah!
pOCket Monsters
Wonder Voyage
Waah!
Amazing! We’re flying!
That was a little scary,
but it was really fun!
Have you settled down now?
Whoa!
Huh?!
When they started flying,
I began wondering if...
...maybe these aren’t
Mototokage!
Liko! Roy!
Huh?
Sorry for suddenly disappearing,
Masquernya.
Oh, sorry...
Ohh, I feel sick...
There’s no doubt about it.
This is Koraidon,
said to be the ancestor of Mototokage.
Koraidon?
Yeah. I’ve seen only a single one before,
but it’s a Pokémon that shouldn’t normally
exist in the present day.
But what brings it here?
The other one
I’ve never seen before...
Could it be Miraidon,
of which only scant records remain?
Miraidon!
Koraidon! Miraidon!
Don’t fight!
The first ones to break through the harsh mountain roads
of South Area 5 and reach the first checkpoint...
...are, unsurprisingly,
the top two teams:
Mover Foods and Paldea Postal!
Tobashitenno-san, don’t you think it’s about time
you handed over that red winner’s jersey?
You never give up, Kitte.
If you want it, you’ve gotta
show your stuff and take it from me!
I’ll be taking that mountain prize jersey
off you, Noborio!
If you say so!
Huh? Maybe they’re
actually getting along...?
Of course! I think I still have...
Got it!
Huh?
Me too!
What a relief!
Have Navi’s too!
And mine!
Here!
It ate it!
Have more and more! And this!
I’ve still got more for you!
Me and Yamirami ate all mine,
so I don’t got nothin’ for ya!
Here. Go give them mine.
Huh?!
I didn’t care one bit about
joinin’ in though, you hear? Geez!
Are you saying
we can ride you again?
You want to race?
Go on and do it, kids!
You won’t get this chance again!
Right!
Give it your best shot!
Now then, how about
we meet them at the finish line?
Yeah!
Now, the leading racers
have entered Cercle Town.
Once they leave the town and head east,
they’ll finally be at their goal of Table City!
Go, go, Mover Foods!
Tobashitenno, blast it!
Mototokage! Trailblaze!
And Competitor Keshiin
of Paldea Postal makes her move!
Not on my watch! Agility!
But Competitor Tyler
doesn’t miss a beat!
She’s got her signed and sealed!
You’re not getting past me that easy.
Dra-gone!
Oh my! A sudden accident!
Swerving to avoid a Puppymocchi that leaped out
in front of them has led to a humongous crash!
Are you okay, Mototokage?
How will this time loss
affect the race results?!
Huh?
Honk-honk! Honk-honk!
Astoundingly, the first-time entrants
of the Dragon Biker Gang have caught up!
We’ve come all this way to be here!
We’re not leaving empty-handed!
The race is almost over!
Currently leading the pack is, unbelievably,
the Dragon Biker Gang!
Right on their heels, the prior champions Mover Foods,
as well as Paldea Postal, are in hot pursuit!
Let’s go!
And the sprint for the finish
has begun!
This race will be decided by just how much
the sprinters can distract the aces!
Paldea Postal!
Go! Dragon Biker Gang!
Neki!
Leave it to me!
I’ll show you
the fastest delivery in Paldea!
I am the unassailable champion!
Will the glories of victory descend on
Competitor Tobashitenno of Mover Foods?!
Competitor Kitte of Paldea Postal?!
Or possibly even Competitor Neki of
the dark horse Dragon Biker Gang?!
At last, they’re close enough
that they might be seen by the naked eye!
Hmm?
What’s this?!
Liko! Roy!
This’s super intense!
Go for it!
Amazing! The two surprise entrants
from the start of the race...
...are catching up with
the frontrunners at an unreal pace!
What?!
You guys?!
Neki-san!
It’s been so long!
What’re those swanky dragons?
Bwuuuh! There is the unexpected shock
I’d longed to see!
No surprise entrant’s beating me!
I’ll shred anyone who messes with me!
Honk-honk! Honk-honk!
Goal!
As of this moment,
the 103rd Mototokage Race has concluded.
Ahh, that was fun!
It sure was!
We made some lovely memories
with Miraidon and Koraidon, too.
You make pretty good bikers, y’know?
Where did you find those Pokémon o—?
Bwuuuh-huh-hoi-hoi-hoi-hoi-hoi-hoi...
Everyone, that was a marvelous race!
The bonds between man and dragon!
This, truly, is the epitome of what
the storied Mototokage Race should be!
Uuuh...
Ooh, wise words from Mr. Hassaku.
Well, let’s race again
next time we meet, you hear?
Ride on!
Yeah!
Koraidon and Miraidon, huh...?
I hope we meet them again.
If you lot wish to see them,
they’ll show themselves again.
History repeats itself, after all.
Next time, I get to ride ‘em too, right?
Huh?! Wouldn’t that be up to them?
Navi’s hungry now!
Well, I might know a tasty
paella restaurant!
Since we’ve come all this way,
how about I treat you to dinner, too?
All right!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Friede here!
It’s time to Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie!
Today’s topic is Miraidon!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Miraidon
Classification
Type
Height
Weight
Ability
Paradox Pokémon
Electric
Dragon
Hadron Engine
It has various different forms.
Its four-legged form is Limited Mode.
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
So then, how about its floating one?
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
See the answer after the commercials!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Gonna give my motivation button a little tap!
The power of hard work is amazing!
(Ahem!)
But if I slack off I might end up devolving...
Well, that’s no good!
But now you mention it...
I know button mashing won’t help at all
So stop shaking this maiden’s heart already
(Stop it!)
Getting attached, but then they turn away
When things just don’t go the way that you want...
Isn’t it so fun? Doesn’t it make your heart race?
Doesn’t it make you all excited?
When I feel a spark...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
Face to face with the dream I’ve always imagined...
I’ve got electric jolts running through me!
I’m so lovey-dovey I can’t even move!
When I know change is still inside of me...
I’ll catch it in a Cutesy Capsule
then we can be together forever
We’ll conquer any obstacle!
I know our future will shine!
So let’s be friends!
Pick up you! I want you! Hit chu straight in the heart!
Pick up you! I want you! We’re right at the peak of our adven-chu!!
Oh! One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
One toss makes a red-white-spinny-shaky
Cutesy Capsule
One click makes a rolly-wobbly-all-aflutter
onlooking Street
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Time to announce
the correct answer!
The answer is...
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
Go-Go Mode
Expert Mode
Complete Mode
C: Complete Mode!
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
By keeping its foes in check from above,
it can turn the battle in its favor!
I wonder where those two went...
I hope they’re not fighting.
Mega-Study With Instructor Starmie
Next episode
Let’s all play Squisher-Rules Karuta!
Sure!
Okay!
“To squish is a moment’s happiness,
to squish not a life’s unhappiness.”
Next episode
There, I got it!
Huh?
“A Squisher that trots about
meets a squishy-squishy.”
There, I got it again!
Huh?!
“Pretty as a squishy-squishy,
graceful as a squishy—”
There! Got it yet again!
Next episode
Huh?!
And so, to be continued
next time on Pocket Monsters!
Squishy Pokémon!
When the Squish Gets Squisher, It’s Squish Time!!
Hold on,
I’m not following this at all!
Squishy Pokémon! When the Squish Gets Squisher, It's Squish Time!!
What exactly is
“Squisher-Rules Karuta”?!